All right. What is up, my friends?
Welcome to the complete set review for
Reality Fracture.
[applause]
Really, really cool stuff. This set
looks awesome. And we're going to go
over every card in the entire set, both
constructed and limited. And of course,
you missed white. That was the first
section. Uh, go watch on YouTube. Like,
comment, subscribe, support the content.
Uh Nicole's actually putting that up on
YouTube literally right now for all you
YouTube folks. So we're uh don't worry,
you're not that behind. Okay? And I go
over the cards, go over the awards, you
know, and love and uh and so on and so
forth. Be going to be a really good
time. And uh it's really it. Remind you
all about 10 new brews happening on
Wednesday, of course. Uh it's going to
be uh next Wednesday in early access.
And the release of the set will be on
the 29th where we'll have our first two
drafts. So make sure you see that for
those. And we are brought to you by
>> Cool Stuff, Inc. is proud to sponsor Jim
Davis. We offer [music] great deals on
card games, tabletop RPGs, board games,
and more. Get a free token featuring Jim
Davis, and take 5% off your next order
if you use the code gym 5 at checkout.
Coolstuffin.com. [music]
Cool stuff in stock.
All right, let's do this. Starting out
with Cryo Theory Adapt. Two mana for a
2-1 prowess. Four mana. Exile a card
from the bin and tap a creature and stun
it at sorcery speed. This card's kind of
sweet, honestly. So, blue red, the theme
in the set is uh is prowess, your
typical like prowess theme. And uh
there's a number of support uh
supporting things for that. Also, uh
black blue is like a a self-mill sort of
thing. So, kind of a cool like glue
common good in both those archetypes and
vine in general. And like format stun a
thing is not bad off your two drop. play
it, trade it, and then later on in the
game, it's epic key thing for two turns.
That's pretty great. I think this card's
nice. Really, really good limited two
drop. Uh, not good enough for
constructed, obviously. Um, but yeah,
it's a really, really solid limited two
drop. Uh, could be one of the highest
performing commons I think. Card's
great.
And then we come to uh, Divining
Duelist. Divining Duelist, Divining
Duelist. Three mana, a flash 32. When it
enters, choose one, tap a creature,
untap a creature, or draw a card and
discard a card. And uh this card is in
the set for one reason. That's right.
Spoiler alert. Splinter Twin is on the
bonus sheet. U sorry, not bonus sheet,
the special guests. So there are 10
special guest cards. You will see them
extremely infrequently. There's like one
every like 50 packs, something like
that. So maybe you see one every other
draft period for all the players. So,
they are very very rare and there's 10
of them. So, won't happen very often.
Uh, but the the word of a treat is they
literally designed this common
specifically because Splinter was on the
bonus sheet, which is really fun. I
think honestly it's obviously a fine
limited common. It's not amazing, but
it's fine. It's playable, whatever. Kind
of a filler common, but um you know, you
get you get open up a twin, pick one,
pack one, try and drop three of these,
and all of a sudden now we have uh we
have twin gobo in limited uh which is
kind of fun. So, fill our limited guard,
but that's kind of cool. Uh, sweet. Icy
reception. Ah, yes. Shandra noted uh ice
mage here in the bizarro world. That is
the echoververse.
For an instant, choose one. Uh, mana
leak a creature or legendary spell or
give a creature minus five minus O till
end of turn.
Fine. you know, um, Essence Scatter is,
I think, a playable standard card
despite not being like, you know, very
good. It's a fringe playable card. Uh,
and then being able to counter legendary
permanence means also or legendary
spells, you know, also planes walkers,
whatever else it might be. Um, that
being said, the man league part is kind
of rough, you know, and then has a
buyout of minus 5 minus O much more
relevant in limited, uh, where it's like
kind of an okay trick. I think his card
is just okay. Uh, you know, man creature
in limited is fine but not exciting.
There's also a lot of planes walkers and
stuff. I don't know. I think his card is
just fine. It's a It is counter those
two, I guess. But I don't know. I guess
it's a okay limited card and not too
much more than that. The buyout's kind
of cool. Probably fine. Not a high pick
or anything like that. And the
constructive wise is not very good.
Infinite coursework. Oh man,
>> bummer.
just there's so much homework to do.
It's better for an instant aura uh type
of thing. Loses abilities. This is a
card we see in every limited set. Uh
it's fine removal for limit for for
blue. It's really a good blue rule spell
limited. Not much more than that.
Mindseker Oculus, however, oh boy, is
our bombing common for blue. This card
is awesome. They're metaphor 81 when it
enters empower Jace 4. The hell does
that mean? Well, what it means is you
create one of these, a Jace token. And
similar to amass an army, uh, you
empower Jace 4. If you don't have a
Jace, you make one, put four counters on
it. And if you already have a Jace, you
add four extra counters on it. And Jace
is pretty simple. It's just only
minuses. Minus one to surveil one minus
three draw a card. So basically, you can
shortcut all these empower Jace effects
uh to if it's empower Jace 3, it's just
draw a card. empower Jace two or less.
It's like surveil one. Your opponent can
of course choose to attack it if you
want to, you know, bank up on it. Um,
but the baseline here of simply two one
EDB draw a card is great and the ceiling
is much higher. Uh, there are other
things in the set we'll see that care
about Jace tokens gaining other
abilities. Um, I think the mechanic is
awesome, awesome, awesome, awesome. Uh,
note also that empower Jace means only
the token uh, not a Jace Plains Walker.
So, it doesn't really work in
constructed unless you're copying planes
walker somehow, which can happen, I
suppose. Uh, but yeah, this card's
fantastic. Uh, two-1 draw card and so
much more. Card's great. Big big time
common. Uh, bomb for blue. Constructed
wise, not really good enough. Uh, but as
far as limited goes, this is going to be
probably what your premier common in a
set. And, uh, it's going to play really
cool because the Jace thing plays
really, really well. Like, you're going
to see this in every draft game and in
an awesome fun way. Uh, really, really
fun mechanic.
more empower Jace Proteg's awakening
format for a sorcery empower Jace six
that's a lot and then also draw a card
so form mana to draw two effectively uh
and then leave a third card on the table
which your opponent can then attack
maybe you can defend it uh maybe you
have other things for Jace stuff so
definitely slow and clunky uh you know
sorcery speed four mana draw two is
pretty bad but could be three you know
and then obviously you can do other
things with it so I think I think this
guard's kind of fringe. Uh if you're
playing against a slow controlling deck,
have a lot of removal and quiz to defend
yourself. Sure. But I don't know. I
think attack the J is kind of rough. So
I think this card is only okay and
limited and expected not playable.
Semester for seer format for a three
four creature with prepare just like in
stricks haven. uh enters prepared. You
can cast a spell after playing the
creature. I'm going to enter surveil one
and it is peer review which is a spell
we'll see on a number of different cards
which is a really cool way to use the
prepared mechanic I think. Uh kind of
reducing the complexity of a bit uh
which is very very nice to see and three
man 22 and surveil one. The blue white
mechanic in this set uh for limited is
all about surveilling and triggers off
surveills. This does that twice which is
pretty cool. That being said, uh a you
know, three four creature for four mana
is kind of rough. So, uh limited filler
and not too much more, but it's okay.
Sphinx's approach. That's right. Not the
dragon approach. We're in the echo
verse. Sphinx's approach. Blue one draw
two instant. Then you may exile this
spell and four other spells named
Sphinx's approach from your graveyard.
If you do, search for a sphinx and put
it in play and then shuffle. It could
have any number of cards. Name Sphinx's
approach. Of course, this is a mirror uh
of the dragon's approach card. Blue
wanted to draw two at instant speed.
It's not that bad. Quick study is not
that far off the uh the mark. You could
play 10 of these, I guess, or some large
number and maybe self familiar stuff
yourself. Um
note to yourself, if you open this in
your pre-release or open a foil copy, um
>> do not throw this card out with your
commons and uncommons. Uh I imagine the
a regular common worth a few bucks and
then the foil version is worth like a
lot 10 bucks maybe. So finance alert uh
on that but as it stands for constructed
probably not really there and for
limited I mean draw limit is fine so
it's okay but um yeah then maybe you
know could be a opera thing but uh as a
note the big dragons in the set the
leaders of the hex haven schools uh are
sphinxes and not dragons so there's some
things to do with it
some creepy man Uh, surveillance
fantasm Jace on a bird. Two meta 4 a 2
three defender flying vigilance. As long
as you stride or surveil this turn, it
can attack as in defender and four mana
surveil one. Typical set mechanic
defender. Um, it's not bad because
vigilance means you can kind of poke in,
which is kind of cool. Uh, if you're
surveilling early and often, this is
fine, I think. But I normally prefer my
set mechanic uh to drop blue commons to
have three power and like really block a
lot of stuff. Um yeah, I don't know.
Limited filler. Not that exciting.
Undiluting witness. This is the blue
land cycler. Five mana for a 35 flyer.
Uh spend two mana to give it plus one
plus minus one. Sorry. Has basic land
cycling. I mean again these land cycers
are pretty great. Five mana for 35 flyer
is not that bad. It blocks pretty well,
attacks pretty well. Uh, and then land
cycling is great, too. Very, very solid
common. Uh, good stuff.
Unsummoned. This is a card that has been
in Magic since alpha. You should know
what it does. It's a fine tempo card. In
limited, it is uh, you know, a card you
can be tricky with, but definitely a
card that's not particularly high on raw
power level. So, a card you got to time
right. If you do, will be quite good.
Uh, but if you just got to like burn
this amount to two drop, you're pretty
unhappy with it. So, make sure you uh
make sure you try the try works on your
draft decks. But yeah, already
instructed uh fine limited card one to
watch out for. Uh don't get blown out by
this card. Please don't, you know, go
for your big huge pump spell in the face
of one blue when your opponent's playing
a little weird. Onto the uncommons, we
see Arie, humbled humble scribe. This is
the uh again the the mirrored pair of
the red Arie. Again, in this set, there
are a lot of kind of whatif versions of
cards. the regular on color version and
the offcolor kind of plan or chaos style
version. In packs, you'll see these
together. You'll see both of them and
then see a random third one just to make
it not obvious what you took in your
drafts. Uh but yeah, RNA is the blue
version of the red card. The metaphor a
32. Whenever another non-token creature
you control enters, untap this and it
loots.
That's fine. Fine. Limited card. Uh blue
black does care about graveyard stuff.
Kind of like, you know, thresholdy
things. So, kind of cool there. Just a
fine card on RA. Not that exciting,
though. Just fine. Lutters aren't nearly
as good as they were back in the day in
modern day limited. Long, long time ago
when I first started playing Unlimited,
>> this is bad.
>> Uh, seven edition draft murk litter was
the best blue common because games went
so long and cards were so bad that being
able to filter through your your lands
and your crap was huge. These days, all
cards are good and games are fast. So
looting effect just aren't that
exciting. Kind of just want your lands
and all your spells also get get to the
actual late game. So I don't know. This
card's just fun.
Counter sculpt. I
I don't know what to say about this
card. I literally at points in looking
over the set was ready to give this card
best in show and then also ready to give
it a trap card award.
>> You could have picked a better spot. Um,
it's obviously somewhere in the middle.
You know, that's just how things work.
But blue blue instant effectively is
cancel. This is blue blue one counter
spell empower Jace one.
However, you can behold a Jace to make
it cost one less. So, if you have a Jace
Plains Walker in play or a Jace in your
hand, this is just counter spell period,
which is awesome. Obviously, that's
fantastic. The problem is you have to
actually have a Jace in play. Uh, and
there aren't any one mana cards I'm
aware of. Uh, that empower Jace and give
you that Jace token. And how many Jace
Planaineswalkers are you actually going
to play in your deck? Say you play four,
right? A play set of, you know, the
really good Jace uh, mythic or whatever
else it might be.
Not gonna have in your opening hand that
often, you know? So the big crux on a
counter spell is can I cast it for two
mana on turn two because if you can't
reliably most other counter spells are
better. So
the fact that this is cheap later in the
game when you the point in the game you
least need it to be cheap
is tough and there are many many better
hard counter spells for three mana. Uh
power one is pretty cool but there are
much better upsides too. So, I think
this card is pretty good. I think folks
are going to overestimate how good it
is, but it is still good. So, no trap
card here, no best of and show award
here. Um, in limited, it's pretty good
because you'll have a Jason play a lot
of the time. It is somewhat reliant, I
think, on how good the Jace
Planaineswalkers are. Spoiler, there are
two of them, so we'll see those a bit
later. Um, but yeah, really weird card.
I think it's worse than you think it is.
Yes, you in particular. Um, but yeah,
we're a long ways past cancelelling a
playable card to be totally fair. So,
that's counter sculpt. I uh I just ain't
sure. I tell you, you know,
>> pop quiz shot.
>> And here's Fibble. Still lost. I
This poor guy doesn't know where to go.
So, for a homunculus, it's a one- one.
Whenever one or more opponents are dealt
combat damage during your turn, you draw
two. Your library has no cards in it,
you win the game and it shuffles back
into uh its library. So, important to
note, it sounds like the shuffles back
in is tied to the you win the game,
which is silly because you've already
won the game. It's not. It's basically
just like draw two and then this goes
away. I don't know why it's templated
like that. It's a little It's very
confusing to read. Uh but yes, basically
it's just a one one for two, deal damage
and draw two. So it's kind of like a two
mana draw two turn one turn one one
flyer turn two play this attack and draw
two. That being said, is that good? I
kind of not really honestly, you know.
Um
so so yeah. So I think his card is uh
yeah I guess yeah if it shuffle back
first your library wouldn't be empty. So
yeah I I fine.
It just reads really weird. All right.
Uh but yeah, so um yeah, I think you can
draw there's just better ways to draw
two cards, honestly. Like like chart of
course is legal, you know. So I don't
know. Really cool limited card. I think
the ability to draw two kind of over and
over again is sweet. Uh and then again,
the blue black deck is a self-mill
archetype, so you could maybe win the
game with this. Um but yeah, the card's
fine and limited. Constructed not really
a card, but it's a weird one.
Gist of St. St. Thalia.
The mirrored pair of Thalia. We saw
Thalia in in white. This is the uh the
blue Thalia. So Gist of St. Thalia. Get
it right. Get it? Anyone? You know, Gist
of St. G St. Draft. Um yeah. Better for
a one-two flyer. All your non creature
spells cost one less to cast. It's
artifacts, instant sorceries, and planes
walkers. It's pretty good, honestly. you
know, the body is really bad, but um
it's not too shabby. Uh you know, the
barall effect is pretty powerful as far
as uh you know, making your two mana
spells cost one, yada yada yada. This
can ramp your planes walkers, ramp your
artifacts, make one mana artifacts free.
It's kind of cool. Uh but one two for
two is pretty tough. I don't know.
Interesting card. Um, I don't think it's
good enough for constructive, but I
could be wrong. In limited, if you're
getting a serious reduction, it's pretty
cool. But yeah, overall it's a card that
has some legs. Uh,
sorry. Sorry, Thalia. Maybe maybe it
doesn't have some legs, but
>> keep that shy.
>> It's a cool card.
>> Hatra the desert frost. Another uh
shifted card here for a 43 when it
enters for each opponent's tap uh
creature and stun it. It's a great
limited card. Just Burkstrider and then
three mana untap a creature. Yeah, it's
fine. Um fine limited card comes in.
Burkstriders battles really well or
battles pretty well at least. Um not
amazing, not a super high pick, but good
tempo card for limited. That's really
it.
Perfected theory one blue instance.
Choose one target base power 1 one or
four five till end of turn. I mean it's
a pretty cool card. Uh, you can turn to
frog your opponent's creature and make
it shrink and win a combat against it,
or you can make your 22 into a four five
and win a combat the other way. So, I
think this is a pretty sweet limited
card. Um, the fact that it can be a a
combat spell on both sides of the ball
is pretty cool where it's not just a
pump and just a shrink. Um, yeah, it's a
good card. This is a good limited card.
Probably it's probably not good enough,
although it could, you know, maybe not
out of their own possibility. Uh, but
yeah, for a limited card, it's great. uh
noting it stacks under prowess and other
plus encounters and things like that
like that too. Uh so those all go on top
of the uh the base four five which is
cool. Yeah, it's cool. Good card. Cool
art too.
Plan for all outcomes for mana
enchantment when it enters the owner of
up to one other target non-land
permanent puts it on the top or the
bottom. So usually this is an instant
and a common this is an uncommon version
of it sorcery speed. Whenever you cast
your first non-creature spell each turn,
empower Jace one.
Pretty cool. So, effectively tacking uh
surveil one onto all your spells or your
first spell, I guess, each turn, but
could build up and draw cards. Can, you
know, plays well with other empower Jace
cards. I guess card is pretty cool. I
think you're getting enough off the back
side of this where the the front side
being slow and clunky is kind of okay.
Um, it is slow and clunky, but it's kind
of cool. Cool for controlling decks and
spell heavy decks.
I think it's going to be okay. Not
amazing, just okay.
Precise redaction. This is your color
hoser for black and white. This is flash
freeze just in a different world.
Counter a white or black spell. Of
course, just like flash freeze, this
will be a playable sideboard card in
some formats and not in others.
You get the idea. I don't think too
crazy here.
Profs consulting detective two for a 22
uncommon. If you scrier surveil, you may
pay two. And if you do, put a counter
miss and draw a card.
It's pretty good. Um, Prof is just a
good limited signpost for the blue white
archetype. Uh, at a super low
opportunity cost, you'd get one trigger
off this get a three, three for four and
draw a card. It's pretty good. So, it's
not limited card. Not good enough for
constructed, but very, very solid.
Roric Thar, Biomagus. Uh,
>> I bet you weren't expecting that one.
God,
>> the mono blue Roricthar six mana for a 4
six flyer has prowess. Prowess, which is
obviously a big game. Whoever becomes a
target of smaller ability opponent
controls, draw a card. Uh, excellent,
excellent limited card. You play this
thing, it's huge. It blocks pretty well.
If you untap, you might just one-shot
your opponent and if they kill it, you
draw a card. Great. Awesome. Great
limited card. Great top end card. Don't
want like a million of these. Uh but
really really solid boom boom. Uh as far
as limited goes cards great
tsuku umawa fugitive. We have a reprint
here. Uh one three for for two. All your
one or less less power things are
unblockable. It's an okay limited card.
Not particularly powerful but not a bad
way to push things through. You know
what this card does and then limited
traos academy guardian form for a 15.
This spell costs two less to cast if
you've cast a non-creature spell vister.
Has flying vigilance and prowess.
>> Good lord
gigantism.
>> This card's kind of nice. Um, just play
any spell and you have two mana for a
one five flying vigilance prowess.
Blocks insanely well. Attacks pretty
good, too. Yeah, card's nice. Cool card.
It being an artifact is not particularly
relevant in this cell in this set. Um,
the card's dope. And then, uh, the cool
about this card also is this card turns
on Mox Opal, Mox Amber, and Mox Jasper.
>> The Mox Trifecta. Uh, it's good with all
of them being a dragon, an artifact, and
a legendary. So, that's kind of cool.
Um, yeah, cool. Cool. Limited card.
probably not insane for constructed
where like the Mox synergy is pretty
real and obviously it plays great with
Mox because you play a Mox and play it
for two. Um probably not good enough in
those formats but maybe Pioneer honestly
like a Mox Mox amber Mox Jazz probably
not but maybe a fun episode of Freshly
Brewed in the future. Then we come to
our way enchantments. There are two of
these for each color and they empower
Jace and they give Jace different
abilities. Way of the Carromancer is
three mana for a enchantment. Uh,
empower Jace five and gives all your
planes walkers minus three. When you
next cast an instant or sorcery spell
this turn, copy that spell and you may
choose new targets with a copy. Much
more finicky than the white ones we saw
uh where, you know, you got to like have
a spell you want to copy
uh set up for this, have your Jace live,
yada yada yada. If you play Jace and
draw a card, you can't do the copy
effect. I think his card's kind of
stinky. Uh maybe kind of cool if there
is some sort of like, you know, cool
spell-based really heavy Jace limited
deck, but I think overall this card is
uh is kind of meh, kind of unexiting. Uh
pretty low floor.
However, Way of the Mind Sculptor is the
other one. Five mana for an enchantment.
Again, empower five. Whenever you
activate a loyalty ability, if you
remove two or more loyalty counters to
activate it, draw a card. And that is
actually quite nice. Uh, so again, it's
any loyalty ability, not just the Jace
token ability. So if you have other
planes walkers in play, this thing goes
kind of nuts as far as drawing cards.
And base level, this is five mana for a
Jace token uh at two ult draw two, which
is, you know, pretty solid overall. So
definitely a little fragile to be able
to defend the card properly. Uh, but
it's pretty cool. Pretty pretty high
upside limited. constructed is probably
not good enough, but it's a cool card.
[laughter]
I am the Watcher. Welcome to Marvel.
What if Yargle didn't skip leg day?
Yargle, Goliath of Otaria. And uh this
is the uh this is the of course mirrored
pair Jarle where what if Yargo went to
and you know went to leg day all the
time. Five mana for a vanilla 3 39 and
uh I mean 39 isn't the best stat line
for for limited uh there is some things
that care about toughness. If you are
playing a very defensive uh limited deck
defending your Jaces or whatever this
thing does block pretty well. It's cute
with the white Gala,
but you know, it's just kind of okay. I
think this card will be about as good as
the Black Yargle is in Limited. And
spoiler alert, that card is a miss also.
Uh, but yeah, I don't know. It's
amusing.
Uh, Euro hope from the shadows. One mana
for a blue one one flash. When Euro
enters, choose one. Tar gets plus minus
Z gets minus X minus O to end of turn. X
number cards in your graveyard or
surveil two.
And yeah, I mean this card's pretty
good. We've seen this sort of like, you
know, one one for one flash give a thing
minus two minus O be a fringe playable
limited card, but the fact that this
also can surveil too, which not only is
fine at a base value, but can also
trigger your surveil effects in your
blue white fateold deck is pretty sweet.
And in your the blue black deck, which
cares about graveyard stuff, this might
give minus five minus six. So card's
pretty cool. Uh it's not overtly
powerful, but it's pretty tricky. This
is the kind of card that really good
limited players will use to uh to good
effect, but I would not take it too
high. And then in limited uh instructed,
I mean, I guess cards, it's kind of meh,
but um yeah, it's cool.
On to our rares. Cruel calculations
for a sorcery. Draw X or X the number of
cards that were put into a player's
graveyard of their library this turn. I
mean, if that's not bait, I don't know
what is. Uh, just
>> just spring in the trap.
>> That's it. I'm going to clone.
>> Another card with an insanely high
ceiling and an insanely low floor. Uh,
you know, if you were to glimpse the
unthinkable, then you could draw 10. Uh,
but of course, if you don't mill them or
kill their things, you draw zero. So can
target yourself or you can self mill
which is kind of cool but yeah I think
this card is just too finicky for a
serious play constructed unlimited it's
probably fine you know uh know that it
is target player so unfortunately
uh say you attack and they block and you
trade in combat you can't draw two
because it's you got to pick one
player's graveyard which is tough but
yeah uh I think this card is pretty
sketch um for serious structed for more
casual stuff sure at instant speed
maybe. Uh but yeah, overall I think this
card is I don't know. You know, there's
a number of mil three effects in limited
for blue black, but it's just so much
work. So, I don't know. Not really a
huge fan. I'm sorry. It's it's from
library. My bad. I
you
read other card. Uh it's specifically
from a player's library, [music] not
from anywhere. So, only works with
milling. Uh so, yeah, there is mill
stuff in blue black, but yeah, I don't
know. We're gonna move on to a card
that's uh that's better hopefully in
divider of victory. One blue for a
prepared one- one of you scrier surveil
plus un of turn. It has unwind history
to sorcery bounce a creature man three
or less and surveil one. Scri's pretty
good. Um a one drop that can just bounce
a thing like and then attack for two on
turn two is kind of cool. Good against
tokens. I worry this card just isn't
good enough for constructed where you're
not getting enough of payoff. Um, if the
Scrier Surveil gave it a permanent plus
one counter, I think this card would be
insane. Um, but it's temporary.
I think it's fringe constructed playable
and limited is pretty great, I think.
Uh, where, you know, again, the blue
white mechanic is all about sliver
stuff. Bounce things pretty cool. There
are some tokens, too. Kind of a weird
rare. Uh, it feels more like an uncommon
to me. Maybe it being rare is uh is Wati
kind of saying, "Hey, this card's
actually pretty good." Um, but yeah, I
don't know. Card's cool, but
it's a little underpowered.
And then we come to our rare Jace.
>> Jace is here. And of course, uh, you'll
see Jace in many games as a token, but
there are two real Jace cards in the
set. We have Jace reality sculptor, not
the mind sculptor. Five mana for a five
loyalty Jace has plus one empower Jace X
where X is the number of islands you
control. So if you're playing Monlue uh
you're going to empower Jace five which
will give you a five loyalty token. You
can draw a card of it immediately which
is kind of cool. Uh
kind of a monolue coded card, but we'll
see. Has minus three until your next
turn whenever a creature attacks you or
a plan control gets minus five. So it
can like kind of fog the board for a
turn, which is kind of cool actually.
And then as a zero mana ultimate,
>> exile all with the bottom card of each
opponent's library, activate only if
there are 25 or more loyalty counters
among Jesus you control. So if you are
empowering Jace a whole bunch or you are
just playing a variety of Jaces from
older formats or whatever or the other
Jason set, uh is there a Jace currently
in standard? So, the two mana uh outlaws
Jace is the only one that's not the the
mythic one and miss sets. There are
three total Jace potentially in the
format. And of course, the empower Jace
as well. Uh that's not accounting for
copying whatever. And of course, older
formats have a bunch of other Jaces too.
So, kind of a cool card. Uh again, the
fact that it's tied to islands a little
rough because if you want to play some
sort of like super friends deck, you
know, it's a little weird. Um but yeah,
the fact that it doesn't win the game
instantly is a big deal, too. uh where
you know you ultimate this if you can't
make them draw and just say go they
might stack and kill you. I don't know.
It's a pretty cool card. Um it's weird.
It is definitely weird. Uh but yeah, 25
loyalty or more.
I'm not sure. It's a weird one. My gut
says the card isn't that good, but it
does it is pretty cool and pretty fun.
So, uh so we'll see. Jace Reality
Sculptor and then uh in limited cards is
pretty great, I think, as long as you're
playing out of violence. But yeah,
then we go to the card that makes uh the
last card really sweet and is a pretty
cool card in general. In Jayce's
minations, you met for an instant until
end of turn. You may activate loyalty
abilities of Jace Plains walkers you
control. On any player's turn, anytime
you can cast an instant and you empower
Jace eight,
>> eight
of
>> Jace. Um, so at absolute floor value,
this is endstep, empower Jace 8, draw a
card, untap, draw a card. So you have
three mana, draw two, empower Jace 2,
which is pretty good. Honestly, I think
that's a pretty sweet card. Uh, and then
of course, if you are playing other Jes,
you can activate those. So you can play
this thing on their turn, plus this
Jace, plus that Jace, draw off your
other Jace. Pretty cool. Uh, and there's
also a combo with this card. Yeah, with
with Kasmina, which copies other abil
which gives other abilities other
things. A lot of cool things happening
here basically. Uh, but I think the card
is really good. Uh, could have won the
sleeper award. Honestly, I don't recall
what I gave a sleeper a reward to in
blue. Uh, we're going to find out, I
guess. But, um, I think this card is
pretty sweet. I think this card is
really, really nice. The base rate is
quite good. The ceiling is super high. I
think it's good limited, good
constructed. Uh, this card's cool. Very,
very nice card. Um, maybe she should
have won the sleeper award, but it also
looks really good, too. It's not a
sleeper, actually. But card's great.
Lyra, Taran, Archangel. All right, so
Lyra, we got a monol blue angel here.
Blue one for A3 flyer. The end of each
end step, if you've drawn three or more
cards this turn, make an angel token.
And then five mana to end of turn,
whenever liar deals damage to a player,
draw two cards. Uh, so that would be the
third card. So, I mean, pretty insane
limited card, right? Just a three- three
flyer over three that will start drawing
you cards and making tokens on turn
five. That's kind of guess. Um, has to
live to do stuff, you know, it's not
like a trigger.
Yeah, I mean, this card is pretty cool.
I don't think he gets there constructed,
but I think it limited his cards.
Whimmel will slam first bomb. Um, yeah,
it's kind of cool. Cool card.
Sammit, Tyrant of Nakatuman.
Maybe
>> you're saying it wrong.
>> Hopefully. And uh what we do have here
though, folks, is our trap card. Uh I
know you CDH players are going bananas.
Uh but metaphor 821 rare. It's a human
wizard that simply gives all of your
instance and sorcery spells split
second. So, if you're unfamiliar with
split second because you weren't around
20 years ago during time spiral, um
split second means that your opponent or
nobody uh can respond to a thing with
split-second. It can still trigger
triggered effects. So, for example, if
you have a prowess effect in play, uh
you can respond to the prowess effect of
the actual spell. Um right,
so triggers.
Does that work? Actually,
>> I look like a jackass.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, needed a refresher here. So, split
second means as long it's just read the
card, I guess.
Split second means as long as a spell
split second is on the stack, you can't
do anything basically. Uh, so the the
caveat here is that things will trigger.
Say prowess effect triggers off of this,
you can't respond to the prowess trigger
either. The thing is that say there was
a a card that said, you know, whenever
you play a spell, counter it. That would
still counter a spell. Uh because the
triggers can still affect the spell. You
just can't actually re respond to it. So
that's going on here. So this is
basically a spell a two-1 that makes all
yourself uncounterable and is a little
bit more than that. That being said,
um
is very good. Like, you know, this guard
is a lot worse than uh the hex goblin,
which sees, you know, very very fringe
play. That's a 2 two with a ward
ability, uh which is a lot more um and
this is just a vanilla to window combat
abilities kind of whatever. So, this is
a very narrow card in that it simply
just, you know, makes things
uncounterable, unreactable to. Uh you if
you're a CDH person, go nuts. Uh have
fun. But as far as like serious standard
play, there's just not that many counter
spells in the format. This is super easy
to kill. It's super fragile. I think
guard is mostly unplayable. Uh maybe in
extreme eternal format examples like CDH
or maybe vintage or legacy, sure, but
yeah, overall I think this card is
mostly unplayable. Um it's not even
non-creature, so like you can't even
like, you know, use it to sneak in your
artifacts or planaineswalkers or
whatever else too. Yeah, it's whatever
honestly. maybe a sideboard card for
your control mirrors if some sort of
draw go control mirror ends up being a
thing. Um but yeah, cool thing here is
yeah, I guess you can lightning bolt a
psychic frog in modern with this card in
play which is kind of cool turning into
a sudden shock or whatever. But uh yeah,
there you go. Savage a tyrant of
whatever uh is your trap card and not
great limited either. It's the body's
not very good.
Sinks of false conclusions format for a
42 flash flying. Whenever it attacks,
you loot. Whenever it dies, if it's not
a token, make a token that's a copy of
it.
I mean, it's not bad, right? Like, just
flashes in, block a big thing, and then
just have another one. I don't know what
deck wants this card as far as
constructive goes. Um, of course, Momo
is the uh the go-to for any flyer, but
having Flash, like Momo and Flash don't
play very well together. So, this card
is busted and limited, right? Like they
attack with their four drop, you just
flash it and block and then just end up
with a 42 flyer with a good ability. Um,
you know, but that being said, is there
a construct that wants this card? I
don't really think so, but maybe, you
know, the raw rate isn't really good
enough. I don't know, honestly. you
know, hard to find out if they want this
card. Could be like a cyborg duke and a
control deck or something like that. Uh,
but yeah, pretty powerful on raw rate.
Uh, great card in limited, you know,
torch tower is rotating pretty soon, so
any cheap exile effect is a big deal.
Uh, but there are always the exile, too,
if you want to beat it that way. So, I
don't know. It's a pretty powerful card.
I just don't know where it goes.
Theorist proxy. It's a metaphor in 03
flash when it enters empower Jace 3. So
again baseline just draw a card one blue
sack this the next spell you cast this
turn can't be countered. I mean if you
really want this effect in standard just
play the land right the mistrise
village. So I think this card is not
particularly exciting in constructed. Uh
unlimited is also not very exciting
because it just an 03 but draws a card
which is kind of whatever. So pretty
weird card. Uh not really about it.
Variable chaser the metaphor a two three
flying prowess enters prepared has arc
of fortune the sorcery not wheel of
fortune uh each player card their hand
draw seven it just is wheel of fortune
um that being said wheel of fortune is
you know kind of a risky weird card uh
they also don't need to it's a may I'm
sorry it's not exactly wheel of fortune
so you can't use it uh in your narits or
your shielder deck unfortunately
[cheering]
which you really really evil folks
clearly want to do. You know, you're
going to be that kind of rude. Whatever.
Uh it is what [music] it is. But um
yeah, I don't know. It's fine. You know,
like Wheel of Fort is a weird card to
use. Wheel of Fortune effects aren't
that good uh without that kind of
synergy. So, I don't see like a fun card
in Limited. Seems like a kind of an
exciting card overall. Um
yeah, whatever.
Then we come to our mythics
and we come to our best in show for blue
Shandra chill of compliance of course
the mirrored pair to Shandra torch of
defiance. Uh more on that a little bit.
Uh this is a three-minute plan walker
with four abilities. Blue one three
loyalty two plus abilities. First one's
surveil one. Then if you put a non
creature nonland card into your
graveyard this way put it in your hand.
So basically if your top card is a non
non-creature nonland, you just draw it.
So three mana for a planaineswalker that
pluses one to draw a card maybe
twothirds of the time if you built your
deck right is pretty buck wild. Uh
that's pretty good. And then plus one to
add a blue only for non-creature spells
that can ramp you into planaines
walkers, artifacts, sweepers.
That's a lot of good stuff too. That's
pretty awesome. You can minus X tap a
creature and stun it for X counter so it
can defend itself. And then minus 6 you
get an emblem where uh whenever you cast
a spell, draw a card.
This card just looks awesome. Um
it kind of does a little bit of
everything. Uh it makes mana. It draws
cards. It can, you know, affect the
board a little bit by stunning. It's
cheap.
Card looks great to me. Um, I really
like the idea that it it plays well with
Planaineswalkers where this is a blue
ramp card. Play this on turn three. You
can cast like Elmith on turn four or
something like that, which is great. Um,
I am a little worried about
Planaineswalkers in standard in general
uh because the speed and power level of
standard is not very conducive to uh to
planes walkers in general. We have a top
five planaineswalker of all time. That's
right. All time in standard right now in
Delenfell and it's like barely playable.
So not everybody can do the format for
planes walkers right now. Uh so that's a
bit about count against Shandra, but
Shandra checks every other box. Uh and
of course you know whether you're
playing blue white or blue black or blue
red a lot of possible removal spells to
keep this thing alive. Card seems great.
If it's a trap I am falling right into
it.
>> I'm stupid. You're smart.
>> But we'll see. I think Shandra's
awesome. Uh, great card, best in show,
great in limited, too. Although a little
worse unlimited as far as like you won't
have as many non-relands.
Uh, but the tap effect's better in
limited. So, it's pretty good. And yes,
I think Don Fell's top five all time.
Uh, that's a topic for another day. Then
then we come to our actual sleeper card,
Seasoned [snorts]
Cryommancer. This is of course the not
mirrored but you know uh what if version
of season pyromancer blue one for a
creature two two EDB draw two discard
two. So of course blue loots not
rummages. Discard one or more non-land
cards this way. You can tap that many
creatures and stun them. And this card's
pretty sweet. Also has five mana exile
card from your graveyard and draw two
which is a lot better uh than make two
one ones. Uh kind of awesome and plays
well with the instant speed nature of
blue. cards pretty nice. I think you'd
want to be uh discarding cards for some
sort of value. Uh but this card does
that really really well. Uh we have a
lot of these three mana draw two discard
two cards in standard. Uh but stunning
stuff is really good. This buys you a
ton of time. Uh really really potent.
And then of course, you know, ways to
discard whether you're superior
spider-maning, whether you're monument
of endurancing, uh, flashing stuff back,
whatever else it might be. Pretty cool
tool. So, I think this card is pretty
nice. Five mana draw is pretty awesome.
Uh, just a pretty good card, you know,
definitely not a card that gets there on
raw rate. Definitely needs to be played
with synergy stuff. The card's awesome
and bonkers and limited. Uh, just five
mana draw from your bin is fantastic.
And then, of course, Stunning Things is
great, too. uh card's awesome. Really,
really good. Big fan.
And then we come to uh the theorist Jace
Bellin. This is the mythic version of
Jace. Really quite potent for man for
planes walker three loyalty. Has the
static ability of each opponent's draw
step you draw a card. So effectively
this is just like draw one card every
turn without using an ability at all
which is very very good. Plus one to
make an illusion token so it defends
itself. Minus two to bounce an
artifactic creature. Great. Uh for
opponents only. Can't bounce your own
stuff. Uh and then minus six draw three
and then make all your things huge uh
creature wise. Just that first two
parts of a text box of draw one each
turn uh and then make a token each turn
going up is pretty good. You know, I
don't think it's board dominating, but a
really solid piece of a puzzle. Uh
whether you're playing control deck or
again whether you're playing sort of
super friend deck. There are a bajillion
planainesw walkers in a set and uh this
plays really well with with Elizabeth
making extra tokens or whatever else it
might be. Cards quite good. Bonkers
unlimited. Um pretty cool seeing this
card in either a control shell or in a
uh or like a tokeny shell or like a
super friend shell. This card is very
very good. Uh, theoros Belrin face guard
of a set. Um, yeah, it's just a really
good card. So, to recap for blue, Sound
Compliance is your best in show.
Seasoner is your sleeper card. Salmon is
your trap card and Mineseker Oculus is
your bombing common black is up next.
Please make sure you like, comment,
subscribe, support the content. As
always, a lot of work goes with set
review and your support makes that
possible. And of course, we got 10 new
brews happening on Wednesday. Hope to
see you there. 2 p.m. sharp. 10 new
brews. First time playing the format. I
am pumped, pumped to brew with the set.
And of course, if you're in the Discord,
if you're a pile driver, don't be shy
about telling me what you want to see in
10 new brews. Blocks coming up. Let's
go.